Personal

Name

Marcin Rumanek

Address

Krasne 782M 36-007 Krasne, Rzeszów, Poland

Phone number

+48 606 921 929

Email

marcin.rumanek@gmail.com

marcinrumanek.github.io

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/marcinrumanek

Skills

Python, pandas, scikit-learn, numpy

Data Engineering, ETL, ELT **Basics of Spark, Airflow**

Data Cleaning, Wrangling, Visualisation

Data Analysis, EDA

Basics of Data at Azure

SQL, T-SQL, MS SQL Server

Microsoft Power BI, Power Query, DAX

Languages

Polish Native **English** Fluent German **A2**

Interests

Automotive, Formula 1 Rock and metal music Computer games

Marcin Rumanek

Aspiring BI Engineer/Data Analyst/Data Engineer, trying to start a new career path. Highly motivated and self-driven, loving to learn new things. I have essential skills in SQL, Power BI, Python, data analysis, data engineering, and data science.

Over 10 years of expertise in various industrial automation (PLCs, robots, etc.) projects, including international, multi-language environments. Experienced in customer contacts, leading a small team, tech-lead role, and production data handling.

Work experience

Automation and Robotics Engineer

Dec 2018 - Present

Sure Solutions, Mielec

Conducted many industrial automation projects for various industries from the controls and software side including control system design, PLC, and HMI software development, robot programming, VFDs, servo drive, and vision systems integration allowing the company to successfully provide increased safety and performance, and reduced cost and cycle times for our customers.

Senior PLC Developer

Sep 2017 - Nov 2018

Transsystem, Wola Dalsza

I prepared quotations and took part in technical negotiations, project kick-offs, and other technical meetings providing expert knowledge in controls and automation areas enabling the company to take the role of the main contractor and gain new projects.

Trained, lead, and mentored a small group of young programmers to allow the company to execute smaller projects fully in-house. I prepared PLC and HMI software, and served control systems designers with the required knowledge and expertise.

Automation Engineer

Aug 2016 - Aug 2017

DEC Poland Tekpro, Mielec

Design of automation control systems for powder handling machines. Preparation of electrical diagrams. Creation of project documentation and functional design specification (FDS). PLC and HMI programming.

PLC Software Developer

Jul 2013 - Aug 2016

ISP Polska sp. z o. o., Rzeszów

I was part of big automation projects in the automotive industry in an international, multi-language environment in various locations around the world. I took a team-lead and mentor role for a small team of programmers.

Automation Engineer

Mar 2012 - Jun 2013

PhiLogic, Trzebinia

I took part in various industrial automation projects at all stages: design of control systems, electrical assembly, preparation, and commissioning of PLCand HMI software. I have integrated many automation devices: servos, VFDs, barcode readers, and vision systems.

Automation Engineer

May 2011 - Feb 2012

Nidec Motors&Actuators Poland, Niepołomice

I was taking care of reducing downtime and assuring maximum availability of production machines and equipment by diagnosis, repair, and modifications of electrical control systems and PLC software.

Additionally, I have created electrical and pneumatic schematics for older machines and overseen a database of PLC software backups.

Maintenance Department Assistant

Nov 2009 - May 2011

Nidec Motors&Actuators Poland, Niepołomice

Creation and management of TPM documentation. Support in implementation of new machines.

Certificates

Professional Data Scientist Certificate

2022

DataCamp

Microsoft Certified: Power BI Data Analyst Associate

2022

Microsoft

Education and Qualifications

Master of Science

Sep 2006 - Jun 2011

University of Science and Technology, Kraków

Industrial Automation and Robotics

DataCamp

Jan 2022 - Jul 2022

100+ courses and 350+ hours of lectures, exercises, assessments, and projects in the area of Python Programming, Data Analysis with Python, SQL and Power BI, and Data Engineering.

Technologies/skills learned: Data Mining, Cleaning, Wrangling, Data Visualisation, Hypothesis Testing, Machine Learning, SQL, Python, NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Spark, Airflow, Microsoft Power BI.